<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xmlns="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0 http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0/onedcx_v1.0.xsd">
  <simpleDc>
    <dcterms:type>package</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:creator>Minnesota Population Center</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:title>IPUMS-International: France 1999 Census</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:identifier>ipumsi_6.3_fr_1999_DC.xml</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:subject>Census</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Group Quarters Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Geography Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Economic Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Utilities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Appliances, Mechanicals, Other Amenities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Dwelling Characteristics Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Household Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Other Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Family Interrelationship Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Demographic Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Education Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Migration Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Other Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Occupation Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Industry Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
  </simpleDc>
  <dcTerms>
    <dcterms:dateSubmitted>2014-09-15</dcterms:dateSubmitted>
    <dcterms:available>2014-07-01</dcterms:available>
    <dcterms:abstract>IPUMS-International is an effort to inventory, preserve, harmonize, and disseminate census microdata from around the world. The project has collected the world's largest archive of publicly available census samples. The data are coded and documented consistently across countries and over time to facilitate comparative research. IPUMS-International makes these data available to qualified researchers free of charge through a web dissemination system. The IPUMS project is a collaboration of the Minnesota Population Center, National Statistical Offices, and international data archives. Major funding is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation and the Demographic and Behavioral Sciences Branch of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Additional support is provided by the University of Minnesota Office of the Vice President for Research, the Minnesota Population Center, and Sun Microsystems. Detailed metadata will be found in ipumsi_6.3_fr_1999_ddic.html within the Data Package. The related metadata describes the content of the extraction of the specified sample from the IPUMS International on-line extraction system.</dcterms:abstract>
    <dcterms:tableOfContents>Record type; Country; Year; IPUMS sample identifier; Household serial number; Number of person records in the household; Household weight; Subsample number; Group quarters status; Number of unrelated persons; Urban-rural status; Continent and region of country; 1st subnational geographic level, world [consistent boundaries over time]; NUTS1 Region, Europe; NUTS2 Region, Europe; Region, France [Level 1; consistent boundaries over time]; Ownership of dwelling [general version]; Ownership of dwelling [detailed version]; Fuel for heating; Automobiles available; Number of rooms; Bathing facilities; Household classification; Number of families in household; Number of married couples in household; Number of mothers in household; Number of fathers in household; Head's location in household; Dwelling number; Number of persons in household; Dwelling created by splitting apart a large dwelling or household; Number of persons in large household before it was split; Region; Size of urban unit in 1999; Belongs to federal public housing authority; Main fuel; Number of dwellings; Dwelling category; Type of dwelling; Number of rooms; Occupation status; Move-in date; Belongs to federal public housing authority; Sanitary facilities; Toilet; Location of bathtub and toilet; Main fuel; Method of heating and fuel; Number of cars in the household; Number of persons in the dwelling; Number of persons aged 18 or less; Number of persons aged 24 or less; Number of individuals not part of family; Number of children inthe household; Number of families in the household; Household family structure; Type of household (number of persons); Type of household; Type of household (1990 definition); Record type [person version]; Country [person version]; Year [person version]; IPUMS sample identifier [person version]; Household serial number [person version]; Person number; Person weight; Mother's location in household; Father's location in household; Spouse's location in household; Rule for linking parent; Rule for linking spouse; Probable stepmother; Probable stepfather; Man with more than one wife linked; Woman is second or higher order wife; Family unit membership; Number of own family members in household; Number of own children in household; Number of own children under age 5 in household; Age of eldest own child in household; Age of youngest own child in household; Relationship to household head [general version]; Relationship to household head [detailed version]; Relationship to head, Europe; Age; Age, grouped into intervals; Sex; Marital status [general version]; Marital status [detailed version]; Marital status, Europe; Nativity status; Region of birth, France; Region of birth, Europe, NUTS1; Region of birth, Europe, NUTS2; Citizenship; School attendance; Educational attainment, international recode [general version]; Educational attainment, international recode [detailed version]; Educational attainment, France; Educational attainment, Europe; Employment status [general version]; Employment status [detailed version]; Employment status, Europe; Occupation, ISCO general; Occupation, unrecoded; Occupation, ISCO-1988, 3-digit; Industry, general recode; Industry, unrecoded; Class of worker [general version]; Class of worker [detailed version]; Class of worker, Europe; Sector of employment; Number of employees; Full-time or part-time work; Period seeking work; Region of work, France; Means of transportation to work or school; Migration status, last census; Country of residence last census; Region of residence at last census, France; Person number (within household); Type of Family; Number of people in the family; Number of children in the family; Number of children age 18 or less in the family; Family type; Type of family (definition 1990); Population category; Sex; Age based census year; Age in completed years; Family membership; Relation to family person of reference; Family relationship; Relation to household person of reference; Method of cohabitation; Mode/method of living; Place of birth; Region of birth; Nationality; Indicator of place of previous residence; Enrollment in an academic institution; Region of previous residence; Country of previous residence; Last diploma obtained; Length of job search; Type of employment activity; Part-time; Place of work; Region of place of work; Means of transportation; Wage earner status; Detailed status of working population holding a job; Employment conditions; Professional position; Number of wage earners; Occupation, ISCO; Socio-professional category; Industry; Industry, ISIC; Marital Status; </dcterms:tableOfContents>
    <dcterms:spatial>France</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:spatial xsi:type="dcterms:Box">northlimit=51.091109; eastlimit=9.562218; southlimit=41.364927; westlimit=-4.790282; name=France;</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:temporal>1999</dcterms:temporal>
    <dcterms:references>http://international.ipums.org</dcterms:references>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_fr_1999_ddic.xml</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_fr_1999_ddic_xml.html</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:accessRights>IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved. (see http://international.ipums.org)</dcterms:accessRights>
    <dcterms:modified>2014-12-10T00:00:00</dcterms:modified>
  </dcTerms>  
</metadata>
