<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xmlns="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0 http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0/onedcx_v1.0.xsd">
  <simpleDc>
    <dcterms:type>package</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:creator>Minnesota Population Center</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:title>IPUMS-International: Liberia 1974 Census</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:identifier>ipumsi_6.3_lr_1974_DC.xml</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:subject>Census</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Group Quarters Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Geography Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Demographic Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Fertility and Mortality Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Ethnicity and Language Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Education Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Migration Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Occupation Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Industry Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Other Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
  </simpleDc>
  <dcTerms>
    <dcterms:dateSubmitted>2014-09-15</dcterms:dateSubmitted>
    <dcterms:available>2014-07-01</dcterms:available>
    <dcterms:abstract>IPUMS-International is an effort to inventory, preserve, harmonize, and disseminate census microdata from around the world. The project has collected the world's largest archive of publicly available census samples. The data are coded and documented consistently across countries and over time to facilitate comparative research. IPUMS-International makes these data available to qualified researchers free of charge through a web dissemination system. The IPUMS project is a collaboration of the Minnesota Population Center, National Statistical Offices, and international data archives. Major funding is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation and the Demographic and Behavioral Sciences Branch of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Additional support is provided by the University of Minnesota Office of the Vice President for Research, the Minnesota Population Center, and Sun Microsystems. Detailed metadata will be found in ipumsi_6.3_lr_1974_ddic.html within the Data Package. The related metadata describes the content of the extraction of the specified sample from the IPUMS International on-line extraction system.</dcterms:abstract>
    <dcterms:tableOfContents>Record type; Country; Year; IPUMS sample identifier; Household serial number; Number of person records in the household; Household weight; Subsample number; Group quarters status; Number of unrelated persons; Urban-rural status; Continent and region of country; 1st subnational geographic level, world [consistent boundaries over time]; County, Liberia [Level 1; consistent boundaries over time]; County, Liberia [Level 1; inconsistent boundaries, harmonized by name]; District, Liberia [Level 2; inconsistent boundaries, harmonized by name]; Dwelling number; County or territory; District within county or territory; Type of group quarters; Rural-urban; Record type [person version]; Country [person version]; Year [person version]; IPUMS sample identifier [person version]; Household serial number [person version]; Person number; Person weight; Relationship to household head [general version]; Relationship to household head [detailed version]; Age; Sex; Marital status [general version]; Marital status [detailed version]; Children ever born; Children surviving; Number of births last year; Number of own children in household; Nativity status; Country of birth; County of birth, Liberia; Citizenship; Ethnicity, Liberia; School attendance; Literacy; Educational attainment, international recode [general version]; Educational attainment, international recode [detailed version]; Years of schooling; Educational attainment, Liberia; Occupation, ISCO general; Occupation, unrecoded; Occupation, ISCO-1968, 3-digit; Industry, general recode; Class of worker [general version]; Class of worker [detailed version]; Relationship to head; Sex; Age; Marital status; County or country of birth; Length of residence in years; Citizenship; Tribal affiliation; Literacy; School attendance; Highest degree completed; Children at home; Children ever born; Children surviving; Births last year; Economic activity; Work status; Occupation (2-digit); Industry (3-digit); Industry (1-digit); Locality size (localities with population); </dcterms:tableOfContents>
    <dcterms:spatial>Liberia</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:spatial xsi:type="dcterms:Box">northlimit=8.512782; eastlimit=-7.3684; southlimit=4.343609; westlimit=-11.492327; name=Liberia;</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:temporal>1974</dcterms:temporal>
    <dcterms:references>http://international.ipums.org</dcterms:references>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_lr_1974_ddic.xml</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_lr_1974_ddic_xml.html</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:accessRights>IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved. (see http://international.ipums.org)</dcterms:accessRights>
    <dcterms:modified>2014-12-10T00:00:00</dcterms:modified>
  </dcTerms>  
</metadata>
