<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xmlns="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0 http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0/onedcx_v1.0.xsd">
  <simpleDc>
    <dcterms:type>package</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:creator>Minnesota Population Center</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:title>IPUMS-International: Slovenia 2002 Census</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:identifier>ipumsi_6.3_si_2002_DC.xml</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:subject>Census</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Group Quarters Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Geography Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Utilities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Dwelling Characteristics Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Household Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Economic Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Appliances, Mechanicals, Other Amenities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Other Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Family Interrelationship Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Demographic Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Fertility and Mortality Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Education Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Migration Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Other Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Occupation Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Industry Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
  </simpleDc>
  <dcTerms>
    <dcterms:dateSubmitted>2014-09-15</dcterms:dateSubmitted>
    <dcterms:available>2014-07-01</dcterms:available>
    <dcterms:abstract>IPUMS-International is an effort to inventory, preserve, harmonize, and disseminate census microdata from around the world. The project has collected the world's largest archive of publicly available census samples. The data are coded and documented consistently across countries and over time to facilitate comparative research. IPUMS-International makes these data available to qualified researchers free of charge through a web dissemination system. The IPUMS project is a collaboration of the Minnesota Population Center, National Statistical Offices, and international data archives. Major funding is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation and the Demographic and Behavioral Sciences Branch of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Additional support is provided by the University of Minnesota Office of the Vice President for Research, the Minnesota Population Center, and Sun Microsystems. Detailed metadata will be found in ipumsi_6.3_si_2002_ddic.html within the Data Package. The related metadata describes the content of the extraction of the specified sample from the IPUMS International on-line extraction system.</dcterms:abstract>
    <dcterms:tableOfContents>Record type; Country; Year; IPUMS sample identifier; Household serial number; Number of person records in the household; Household weight; Subsample number; Group quarters status; Number of unrelated persons; Urban-rural status; Continent and region of country; 1st subnational geographic level, world [consistent boundaries over time]; NUTS1 Region, Europe; NUTS2 Region, Europe; NUTS3 Region, Europe; Region, Slovenia [Level 1; consistent boundaries over time]; Water supply; Fuel for heating; Telephone availability; Number of rooms; Toilet; Bathing facilities; Year structure was built; Age of structure, coded from intervals; Living area in square meters; Household classification; Number of families in household; Number of married couples in household; Number of mothers in household; Number of fathers in household; Head's location in household; Dwelling number; Number of persons in household; Region; Size of settlement; Rural/urban areas; Ownership of dwelling; Type of housing unit; Number of rooms; Useful floor space; Piped water supply; Sewage system; Toilet in the dwelling; Bathroom in the dwelling; Piped gas supply; Connection to telephone network; Connection to cable TV network; Type of heating; Main source of heating; Type of building with regard to construction; Type of building with regard to use; Year of construction of the building; Number of dwellings in the building; Record type [person version]; Country [person version]; Year [person version]; IPUMS sample identifier [person version]; Household serial number [person version]; Person number; Person weight; Mother's location in household; Father's location in household; Spouse's location in household; Rule for linking parent; Rule for linking spouse; Probable stepmother; Probable stepfather; Man with more than one wife linked; Woman is second or higher order wife; Family unit membership; Number of own family members in household; Number of own children in household; Number of own children under age 5 in household; Age of eldest own child in household; Age of youngest own child in household; Relationship to household head [general version]; Relationship to household head [detailed version]; Relationship to head, Europe; Age; Age, grouped into intervals; Sex; Marital status [general version]; Marital status [detailed version]; Marital status, Europe; Children ever born; Nativity status; Country of birth; Region of birth, Slovenia; Region of birth, Europe, NUTS1; Region of birth, Europe, NUTS2; Region of birth, Europe, NUTS3; Citizenship; Country of citizenship; Year of immigration, categorized; School attendance; Educational attainment, international recode [general version]; Educational attainment, international recode [detailed version]; Educational attainment, Slovenia; Educational attainment, Europe; Employment status [general version]; Employment status [detailed version]; Employment status, Europe; Occupation, ISCO general; Occupation, unrecoded; Industry, general recode; Industry, unrecoded; Means of transportation to work or school; Migration status, 1 year; Migration status, previous residence; Country of previous residence; Years residing in current locality; Region of previous residence, Slovenia; Person number (within household); Region of usual residence; Size of settlement; Place of birth - indicator; Region of birth; Country of birth; Year or period of arrival; Place of previous residence - type; Region of previous residence; Country of previous residence; Duration of residence; Place of residence one year ago; Relationship to reference person of household; Position of the person in the family; Reason for absence from the household; Sex; Age; Legal marital status; Citizenship; Number of children born alive; Level of current school attendance; Location of current school attended; Travel mode to school; Travel duration to school; Educational attainment; Field of educational qualification; Economic activity status; Occupation; Industry; Dependency relationship; Tenure status of residence; Place of work; Frequency of journey to work; Mode of transport to work; Length of journey to work; </dcterms:tableOfContents>
    <dcterms:spatial>Slovenia</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:spatial xsi:type="dcterms:Box">northlimit=46.876245; eastlimit=16.607873; southlimit=45.425818; westlimit=13.383473; name=Slovenia;</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:temporal>2002</dcterms:temporal>
    <dcterms:references>http://international.ipums.org</dcterms:references>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_si_2002_ddic.xml</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_si_2002_ddic_xml.html</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:accessRights>IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved. (see http://international.ipums.org)</dcterms:accessRights>
    <dcterms:modified>2014-12-10T00:00:00</dcterms:modified>
  </dcTerms>  
</metadata>
