<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xmlns="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0 http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0/onedcx_v1.0.xsd">
  <simpleDc>
    <dcterms:type>package</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:creator>Minnesota Population Center</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:title>IPUMS-International: Morocco 1994 Census</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:identifier>ipumsi_6.3_ma_1994_DC.xml</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:subject>Census</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Group Quarters Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Geography Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Economic Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Utilities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Dwelling Characteristics Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Household Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Family Interrelationship Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Demographic Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Fertility and Mortality Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Ethnicity and Language Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Education Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Migration Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Disability Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Other Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Occupation Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Industry Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
  </simpleDc>
  <dcTerms>
    <dcterms:dateSubmitted>2014-09-15</dcterms:dateSubmitted>
    <dcterms:available>2014-07-01</dcterms:available>
    <dcterms:abstract>IPUMS-International is an effort to inventory, preserve, harmonize, and disseminate census microdata from around the world. The project has collected the world's largest archive of publicly available census samples. The data are coded and documented consistently across countries and over time to facilitate comparative research. IPUMS-International makes these data available to qualified researchers free of charge through a web dissemination system. The IPUMS project is a collaboration of the Minnesota Population Center, National Statistical Offices, and international data archives. Major funding is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation and the Demographic and Behavioral Sciences Branch of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Additional support is provided by the University of Minnesota Office of the Vice President for Research, the Minnesota Population Center, and Sun Microsystems. Detailed metadata will be found in ipumsi_6.3_ma_1994_ddic.html within the Data Package. The related metadata describes the content of the extraction of the specified sample from the IPUMS International on-line extraction system.</dcterms:abstract>
    <dcterms:tableOfContents>Record type; Country; Year; IPUMS sample identifier; Household serial number; Number of person records in the household; Household weight; Subsample number; Group quarters status; Number of unrelated persons; Continent and region of country; 1st subnational geographic level, world [consistent boundaries over time]; Region, Morocco [Level 1; consistent boundaries over time]; Province, Morocco [Level 2; inconsistent boundaries, harmonized by name]; Ownership of dwelling [general version]; Ownership of dwelling [detailed version]; Electricity; Water supply; Number of rooms; Kitchen or cooking facilities; Toilet; Bathing facilities; Wall or building material; Roof material; Household classification; Number of families in household; Number of married couples in household; Number of mothers in household; Number of fathers in household; Head's location in household; Dwelling number; Number of persons in household; Region; Record type; Type of lighting of tent; Number of tents; Animal husbandry; Dwelling occupation status; Type of dwelling unit; Wall material; Roof material; Kitchen; Toilet; Bathroom; Traditional bathroom; Water supply; Water supply: spring or well; Electricity; Source of lighting; Tenant status; Number of rooms; Record type [person version]; Country [person version]; Year [person version]; IPUMS sample identifier [person version]; Household serial number [person version]; Person number; Person weight; Mother's location in household; Father's location in household; Spouse's location in household; Rule for linking parent; Rule for linking spouse; Probable stepmother; Probable stepfather; Man with more than one wife linked; Woman is second or higher order wife; Family unit membership; Number of own family members in household; Number of own children in household; Number of own children under age 5 in household; Age of eldest own child in household; Age of youngest own child in household; Relationship to household head [general version]; Relationship to household head [detailed version]; Age; Age, grouped into intervals; Sex; Marital status [general version]; Marital status [detailed version]; Year of birth; Month of birth; Children ever born; Children surviving; Number of births last year; Children surviving from births last year; Number of children dead; Number of own children in household; Number of own children living elsewhere; Number of children living abroad; Nativity status; Citizenship; Country of citizenship; Primary language spoken, Morocco; Literacy; Educational attainment, international recode [general version]; Educational attainment, international recode [detailed version]; Years of schooling; Educational attainment, Morocco; Employment status [general version]; Employment status [detailed version]; Occupation, ISCO general; Occupation, unrecoded; Industry, general recode; Industry, unrecoded; Class of worker [general version]; Class of worker [detailed version]; Years residing in current locality; Employment disability; Person number (within household); Relationship to head of household; Residence status; Sex; Month of birth; Year of birth (Gregorian and Hegirian calendars); Age in years; Marital status; Country of citizenship; Vital registration; Place of birth; Place of previous residence; Duration of residence (in current town/village); Place of residence last year (during the previous Aid Al Adha holiday); Children living at home; Children living elsewhere in Morocco; Children living in foreign countries; Children who died; Children who are alive (born in previous 12 months); Children who have died (born in previous 12 months); Literacy; Level of education / last grade completed (detailed); Level of education (grouped); Employment status; Occupation (1 digit); Occupation (2 digit); Occupation, 3-digit; Industry (2 digits); Work status; Dialect (local language); </dcterms:tableOfContents>
    <dcterms:spatial>Morocco</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:spatial xsi:type="dcterms:Box">northlimit=35.919164; eastlimit=-1.011809; southlimit=20.764100; westlimit=-17.101527; name=Morocco;</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:temporal>1994</dcterms:temporal>
    <dcterms:references>http://international.ipums.org</dcterms:references>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_ma_1994_ddic.xml</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_ma_1994_ddic_xml.html</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:accessRights>IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved. (see http://international.ipums.org)</dcterms:accessRights>
    <dcterms:modified>2014-12-10T00:00:00</dcterms:modified>
  </dcTerms>  
</metadata>
