<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xmlns="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0 http://ns.dataone.org/metadata/schema/onedcx/v1.0/onedcx_v1.0.xsd">
  <simpleDc>
    <dcterms:type>package</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:creator>Minnesota Population Center</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:title>IPUMS-International: Switzerland 1970 Census</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:identifier>ipumsi_6.3_ch_1970_DC.xml</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:subject>Census</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Group Quarters Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Geography Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Economic Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Utilities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Appliances, Mechanicals, Other Amenities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Dwelling Characteristics Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Household Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Technical Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Constructed Family Interrelationship Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Demographic Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Ethnicity and Language Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Education Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Migration Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Occupation Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Work: Industry Variables -- PERSON</dcterms:subject>
  </simpleDc>
  <dcTerms>
    <dcterms:dateSubmitted>2014-09-15</dcterms:dateSubmitted>
    <dcterms:available>2014-07-01</dcterms:available>
    <dcterms:abstract>IPUMS-International is an effort to inventory, preserve, harmonize, and disseminate census microdata from around the world. The project has collected the world's largest archive of publicly available census samples. The data are coded and documented consistently across countries and over time to facilitate comparative research. IPUMS-International makes these data available to qualified researchers free of charge through a web dissemination system. The IPUMS project is a collaboration of the Minnesota Population Center, National Statistical Offices, and international data archives. Major funding is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation and the Demographic and Behavioral Sciences Branch of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Additional support is provided by the University of Minnesota Office of the Vice President for Research, the Minnesota Population Center, and Sun Microsystems. Detailed metadata will be found in ipumsi_6.3_ch_1970_ddic.html within the Data Package. The related metadata describes the content of the extraction of the specified sample from the IPUMS International on-line extraction system.</dcterms:abstract>
    <dcterms:tableOfContents>Record type; Country; Year; IPUMS sample identifier; Household serial number; Number of person records in the household; Household weight; Subsample number; Group quarters status; Number of unrelated persons; Continent and region of country; 1st subnational geographic level, world [consistent boundaries over time]; NUTS1 Region, Europe; NUTS2 Region, Europe; NUTS3 Region, Europe; Canton, Switzerland [Level 1; consistent boundaries over time]; Ownership of dwelling [general version]; Ownership of dwelling [detailed version]; Fuel for heating; Hot water heater; Central heating; Number of rooms; Kitchen or cooking facilities; Year structure was built; Age of structure, coded from intervals; Household classification; Number of families in household; Number of married couples in household; Number of mothers in household; Number of fathers in household; Head's location in household; Dwelling number; Number of persons in household; Dwelling created by splitting apart a large dwelling or household; Number of persons in large household before it was split; Canton of usual residence; Type of household; Category of building; Type of building; Year structure was built; Number of floors (including ground floor); Type of ownership (building); Type of heating; Hot water; Energy used for heating; Energy used for hot water; Number of rooms; Number of connected rooms; Kitchen or kitchenette; Occupancy status of dwelling; Net rent (in Swiss Francs); Record type [person version]; Country [person version]; Year [person version]; IPUMS sample identifier [person version]; Household serial number [person version]; Person number; Person weight; Mother's location in household; Father's location in household; Spouse's location in household; Rule for linking parent; Rule for linking spouse; Probable stepmother; Probable stepfather; Man with more than one wife linked; Woman is second or higher order wife; Family unit membership; Number of own family members in household; Number of own children in household; Number of own children under age 5 in household; Age of eldest own child in household; Age of youngest own child in household; Relationship to household head [general version]; Relationship to household head [detailed version]; Relationship to head, Europe; Age; Age, grouped into intervals; Sex; Marital status [general version]; Marital status [detailed version]; Marital status, Europe; Nativity status; Region of birth, Europe, NUTS1; Citizenship; Country of citizenship; Religion [general version]; Religion [detailed version]; Mother tongue, Switzerland; Educational attainment, international recode [general version]; Educational attainment, international recode [detailed version]; Educational attainment, Switzerland; Educational attainment, Europe; Employment status [general version]; Employment status [detailed version]; Employment status, Europe; Occupation, ISCO general; Occupation, unrecoded; Occupation, ISCO-1988, 3-digit; Industry, general recode; Industry, unrecoded; Class of worker [general version]; Class of worker [detailed version]; Class of worker, Europe; Full-time or part-time work; Means of transportation to work or school; Migration status, 5 years; Person number (within household); Labour force status; Country of citizenship; Place of residence 5 years prior to the census; Place of birth; Citizenship; Location of workplace; Location of place of education; Age; Sex; Marital status; Religion; Mother tongue; Reference person or spouse; Household status (relationship); Profession studied, highest qualification obtained; Present occupation; Present occupation (ISCO); Present occupation (ISCO 3 digit); Position in principal employment; Time worked (hours); Branch of economic activity (industry); Judicial form of the enterprise; Time to commute (travel duration) to work; Round trips (how often) to commute to work; Means of transport (travel mode) to work; Time to commute (travel duration) to school; Round trips (how often) to commute to school; Means of transport (travel mode) to school; Highest level of educational attainment (original values); Highest level of educational attainment (corrected values); </dcterms:tableOfContents>
    <dcterms:spatial>Switzerland</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:spatial xsi:type="dcterms:Box">northlimit=47.806664; eastlimit=10.488209; southlimit=45.829436; westlimit=5.967009; name=Switzerland;</dcterms:spatial>
    <dcterms:temporal>1970</dcterms:temporal>
    <dcterms:references>http://international.ipums.org</dcterms:references>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_ch_1970_ddic.xml</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:hasPart>ipumsi_6.3_ch_1970_ddic_xml.html</dcterms:hasPart>
    <dcterms:accessRights>IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved. (see http://international.ipums.org)</dcterms:accessRights>
    <dcterms:modified>2014-12-10T00:00:00</dcterms:modified>
  </dcTerms>  
</metadata>
